<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bare Metal Platforms on Talos Linux</title>
    <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bare Metal Platforms on Talos Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Rebar</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/digital-rebar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/digital-rebar/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  3 nodes (please see hardware requirements) Loadbalancer Digital Rebar Server Talosctl access (see talosctl setup)  Creating a Cluster In this guide we will create an Kubernetes cluster with 1 worker node, and 2 controlplane nodes. We assume an existing digital rebar deployment, and some familiarity with iPXE.
We leave it up to the user to decide if they would like to use static networking, or DHCP. The setup and configuration of DHCP will not be covered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equinix Metal</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/equinix-metal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/equinix-metal/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites This guide assumes the user has a working API token, the Equinix Metal CLI installed, and some familiarity with the CLI.
Network Booting To install Talos to a server a working TFTP and iPXE server are needed. How this is done varies and is left as an exercise for the user. In general this requires a Talos kernel vmlinuz and initramfs. These assets can be downloaded from a given release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matchbox</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/matchbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/matchbox/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Cluster In this guide we will create an HA Kubernetes cluster with 3 worker nodes. We assume an existing load balancer, matchbox deployment, and some familiarity with iPXE.
We leave it up to the user to decide if they would like to use static networking, or DHCP. The setup and configuration of DHCP will not be covered.
Create the Machine Configuration Files Generating Base Configurations Using the DNS name of the load balancer, generate the base configuration files for the Talos machines:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sidero</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/sidero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/bare-metal-platforms/sidero/</guid>
      <description>Sidero is a project created by the Talos team that has native support for Talos. The best way to get started with Sidero is to visit the website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
