<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud Platforms on Talos Linux</title>
    <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud Platforms on Talos Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/aws/</guid>
      <description>Official AMI Images Official AMI image ID can be found in the cloud-images.json file attached to the Talos release:
curl -sL https://github.com/talos-systems/talos/releases/download/v0.13.0/cloud-images.json | \  jq -r &amp;#39;.[] | select(.region == &amp;#34;us-east-1&amp;#34;) | select (.arch == &amp;#34;amd64&amp;#34;) | .id&amp;#39; Replace us-east-1 and amd64 in the line above with the desired region and architecture.
Creating a Cluster via the AWS CLI In this guide we will create an HA Kubernetes cluster with 3 worker nodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/azure/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Cluster via the CLI In this guide we will create an HA Kubernetes cluster with 1 worker node. We assume existing Blob Storage, and some familiarity with Azure. If you need more information on Azure specifics, please see the official Azure documentation.
Environment Setup We&amp;rsquo;ll make use of the following environment variables throughout the setup. Edit the variables below with your correct information.
# Storage account to use export STORAGE_ACCOUNT=&amp;#34;StorageAccountName&amp;#34;  # Storage container to upload to export STORAGE_CONTAINER=&amp;#34;StorageContainerName&amp;#34;  # Resource group name export GROUP=&amp;#34;ResourceGroupName&amp;#34;  # Location export LOCATION=&amp;#34;centralus&amp;#34;  # Get storage account connection string based on info above export CONNECTION=$(az storage account show-connection-string \  -n $STORAGE_ACCOUNT \  -g $GROUP \  -o tsv) Create the Image First, download the Azure image from a Talos release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DigitalOcean</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/digitalocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/digitalocean/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Cluster via the CLI In this guide we will create an HA Kubernetes cluster with 1 worker node. We assume an existing Space, and some familiarity with DigitalOcean. If you need more information on DigitalOcean specifics, please see the official DigitalOcean documentation.
Create the Image First, download the DigitalOcean image from a Talos release. Extract the archive to get the disk.raw file, compress it using gzip to disk.raw.gz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GCP</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/gcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/gcp/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Cluster via the CLI In this guide, we will create an HA Kubernetes cluster in GCP with 1 worker node. We will assume an existing Cloud Storage bucket, and some familiarity with Google Cloud. If you need more information on Google Cloud specifics, please see the official Google documentation.
Environment Setup We&amp;rsquo;ll make use of the following environment variables throughout the setup. Edit the variables below with your correct information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hetzner</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/hetzner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/hetzner/</guid>
      <description>Upload image Hetzner Cloud does not support uploading custom images. You can email their support to get a Talos ISO uploaded by following issues:3599 or you can prepare image snapshot by yourself.
There are two options to upload your own.
 Run an instance in rescue mode and replaces the system OS with the Talos image Use Hashicorp packer to prepare an image  Rescue mode Create a new Server in the Hetzner console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nocloud</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/nocloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/nocloud/</guid>
      <description>Talos supports nocloud data source implementation.
There are two ways to configure Talos server with nocloud platform:
 via SMBIOS &amp;ldquo;serial number&amp;rdquo; option using CDROM or USB-flash filesystem  SMBIOS Serial Number This method requires the network connection to be up (e.g. via DHCP). Configuration is delivered from the HTTP server.
ds=nocloud-net;s=http://10.10.0.1/configs/;h=HOSTNAME After the network initialization is complete, Talos fetches:
 the machine config from http://10.10.0.1/configs/user-data the network config (if available) from http://10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openstack</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/openstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/openstack/</guid>
      <description>Creating a Cluster via the CLI In this guide, we will create an HA Kubernetes cluster in Openstack with 1 worker node. We will assume an existing some familiarity with Openstack. If you need more information on Openstack specifics, please see the official Openstack documentation.
Environment Setup You should have an existing openrc file. This file will provide environment variables necessary to talk to your Openstack cloud. See here for instructions on fetching this file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaleway</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/scaleway/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/scaleway/</guid>
      <description>Talos is known to work on scaleway.com; however, it is currently undocumented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UpCloud</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/upcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/upcloud/</guid>
      <description>Talos is known to work on UpCloud.com; however, it is currently undocumented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vultr</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/vultr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/cloud-platforms/vultr/</guid>
      <description>Talos is known to work on Vultr.com; however, it is currently undocumented.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
