<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Talos Linux</title>
    <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.6/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Talos Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://talos.dev/docs/v0.6/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Talos?</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.6/introduction/what-is-talos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.6/introduction/what-is-talos/</guid>
      <description>Talos is an open source platform to host and maintain Kubernetes clusters. It includes a purpose-built operating system and associated management tools. It can run on all major cloud providers, virtualization platforms, and bare metal hardware.
All system management is done via an API, and there is no shell or interactive console. Some of the capabilities and benefits provided by Talos include:
 Security: Talos reduces your attack surface by practicing the Principle of Least Privilege (PoLP) and by securing the API with mutual TLS (mTLS) authentication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.6/introduction/quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.6/introduction/quickstart/</guid>
      <description>In this guide we will create a Kubernetes cluster in Docker, using a containerized version of Talos.
Running Talos in Docker is intended to be used in CI pipelines, and local testing when you need a quick and easy cluster. Furthermore, if you are running Talos in production, it provides an excellent way for developers to develop against the same version of Talos.
Requirements The follow are requirements for running Talos in Docker:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Requirements</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.6/introduction/system-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.6/introduction/system-requirements/</guid>
      <description>Minimum Requirements Recommended These requirements are similar to that of kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
