<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Talos Linux</title>
    <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Talos Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What is Talos?</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/what-is-talos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/what-is-talos/</guid>
      <description>Talos is a container optimized Linux distro; a reimagining of Linux for distributed systems such as Kubernetes. Designed to be as minimal as possible while still maintaining practicality. For these reasons, Talos has a number of features unique to it:
 it is immutable it is atomic it is ephemeral it is minimal it is secure by default it is managed via a single declarative configuration file and gRPC API  Talos can be deployed on container, cloud, virtualized, and bare metal platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickstart</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/quickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/quickstart/</guid>
      <description>The easiest way to try Talos is by using the CLI (talosctl) to create a cluster on a machine with docker installed.
Prerequisites talosctl Download talosctl:
curl -Lo /usr/local/bin/talosctl https://github.com/talos-systems/talos/releases/latest/download/talosctl-$(uname -s | tr &amp;#34;[:upper:]&amp;#34; &amp;#34;[:lower:]&amp;#34;)-amd64 chmod +x /usr/local/bin/talosctl kubectl Download kubectl via one of methods outlined in the documentation.
Create the Cluster Now run the following:
talosctl cluster create Verify that you can reach Kubernetes:
$ kubectl get nodes -o wide NAME STATUS ROLES AGE VERSION INTERNAL-IP EXTERNAL-IP OS-IMAGE KERNEL-VERSION CONTAINER-RUNTIME talos-default-master-1 Ready master 115s v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>This document will walk you through installing a full Talos Cluster. You may wish to read through the Quickstart first, to quickly create a local virtual cluster on your workstation.
Regardless of where you run Talos, you will find that there is a pattern to deploying it.
In general you will need to:
 acquire the installation image decide on the endpoint for Kubernetes  optionally create a load balancer   configure Talos configure talosctl bootstrap Kubernetes  Prerequisites talosctl The talosctl tool provides a CLI tool which interfaces with the Talos API in an easy manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Requirements</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/system-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/system-requirements/</guid>
      <description>Minimum Requirements Recommended These requirements are similar to that of kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s New in Talos 0.10</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/what-is-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.10/introduction/what-is-new/</guid>
      <description>Disaster Recovery Talos now supports etcd snapshots and recovery from the snapshotted state. Periodic snapshots of etcd data can be taken with talosctl etcd snapshot command, and in case of catastrophic control plane failure etcd contents can be recovered from the latest snapshot with talosctl bootstrap --recover-from= command.
Time Synchronization The timed service was replaced with a new time sync controller without any machine configuration changes. There should be no user-visible changes in the way new time synchronization process works, logs are now available via talosctl logs controller-runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
