<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Local Platforms on Talos Linux</title>
    <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/local-platforms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Local Platforms on Talos Linux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/local-platforms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Docker</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/local-platforms/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/local-platforms/docker/</guid>
      <description>In this guide we will create a Kubernetes cluster in Docker, using a containerized version of Talos.
Running Talos in Docker is intended to be used in CI pipelines, and local testing when you need a quick and easy cluster. Furthermore, if you are running Talos in production, it provides an excellent way for developers to develop against the same version of Talos.
Requirements The follow are requirements for running Talos in Docker:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QEMU</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/local-platforms/qemu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/local-platforms/qemu/</guid>
      <description>In this guide we will create a Kubernetes cluster using QEMU.
Video Walkthrough To see a live demo of this writeup, see the video below:
Requirements  Linux a kernel with  KVM enabled (/dev/kvm must exist) CONFIG_NET_SCH_NETEM enabled CONFIG_NET_SCH_INGRESS enabled   at least CAP_SYS_ADMIN and CAP_NET_ADMIN capabilities QEMU bridge, static and firewall CNI plugins from the standard CNI plugins, and tc-redirect-tap CNI plugin from the awslabs tc-redirect-tap installed to /opt/cni/bin (installed automatically by talosctl) iptables /var/run/netns directory should exist  Installation How to get QEMU Install QEMU with your operating system package manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VirtualBox</title>
      <link>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/local-platforms/virtualbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://talos.dev/docs/v0.13/local-platforms/virtualbox/</guid>
      <description>In this guide we will create a Kubernetes cluster using VirtualBox.
Video Walkthrough To see a live demo of this writeup, visit Youtube here:
Installation How to Get VirtualBox Install VirtualBox with your operating system package manager or from the website. For example, on Ubuntu for x86:
apt install virtualbox Install talosctl You can download talosctl via github.com/talos-systems/talos/releases
curl https://github.com/talos-systems/talos/releases/download/&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;/talosctl-&amp;lt;platform&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;arch&amp;gt; -L -o talosctl For example version v0.13.0 for linux platform:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
